but winner Jason is with us he's
managing director portfolio Management
Services at JM Financial Services vinay
great to have you with us here thank you
very much
uh just a quick word uh to begin with on
uh I mean I'm looking at what you own
and what you like uh right I mean across
the board making India theme I.T
Services fmcg uh so in the make in India
theme just your thoughts on uh Hal in
this on Aeronautics which I think you
you do own you do like
there are valuations that for uh halvena
and would you assign the same kind of
valuations that capital goods companies
get because if you look at Capital good
valuation they are far higher than
defense manufacturers uh especially the
likes of ABB Siemens Etc because the
industries are broadly overlapping right
the same kind of industry structure go
on
so thank you so much for this question
you know when we looked at the defense
sector first we thought it could be a
secular growth part of our business but
that's when we realized that what the
Indian government is trying to do they
try to make more and more of
manufacturing come into the country uh
replace them from what was being uh
coming in from the rest of the world
into the country so what that would do
is you know that would reduce our import
bill and the dependency on the country
would increase so our perspective why do
we like Hindustan uh Hal uh first reason
uh good growth uh you know of what they
are doing in terms of uh the overall
supply of uh playing second uh more
importantly they just is doing very very
well third India's uh manufacturing the
government's mandate to manufacturing
increase in the country would lead to a
higher ownership for the Indian
manufacturers up from 20 25 to 40 45 so
two trajectories as the Indian pie of
Defense grows HL grows second as the
India
manufacturing space increases and as
Indian planes are made more and more Hal
gains further in terms of valuation the
stock is at one year forward multiples
of 2022. uh for me it's not the growth
of 23 of 24 which is step it but you
know as our analyst tells us the 25 26
growth would be even much higher 15 to
20 percent so this leads it to be a core
owning in our sector moving to your
second question of capital goods uh I
clearly believe uh the valuation of this
company can be a lot better uh it could
be sporadic because the government could
give them orders every one to two years
but they have a order book for the next
three years already filled but when it
comes you know people will keep on
raising earnings estimates and for me
it's a better way to play the industrial
or the captain good sector which is why
we like Hindustan aeronautics uh the
night afternoon uh Rima here just to get
the big picture in you know it appears
to be uncertainty related to China
slowing down or the peak fed hawkishness
is largely in the price we've been
talking about it all over the world for
the last so many months now the earnings
season is largely behind us what are the
triggers the market should be sensitive
to from here on
so so two things you know when we say uh
it's in the price uh you know there's
something which are macro analyst showed
us just yesterday his point was if you
look at nsci India in rupee and msci
India in dollars MSA Indian Rupees is up
a bit and MSA Indian dollars is down
about five to eight percent in the last
year so you've seen a 12 13 plus uh
dollar uh appreciation the rupees move
from 70 and change to 82. so when we see
even the index at 18 000 levels if you
knock it off for the foreign investor
you're probably at 16 500. so we largely
agree with you that uh you know the
markets uh not just world over but India
though it's flat uh foreign foreign
investors as good as being down 14 15
what to look out forward uh again you
know back to what us is doing you know
and U.S is doing a three-point uh
strategy first it's high trades at the
fastest ever rate uh which we've seen in
the last couple of decades 400 basis
increase in the interest rates that's
unprecedented all of it uh you know in a
in a very short period of time now the
question is the next rate hikes could be
slower but there are rate hikes if
earlier analysts or economists felt that
number of interest rate could be you
know peaking at five percent they could
probably look at it peaking at six
percent that makes the U.S currency also
uh you know a lot more attractive
compared to the Indian currency uh the
second is even when you reach that rate
how long will that interest rate remain
at that level and that's where you get
pain or slowdown and U.S coming in and
the third trajectory really is uh you
know when does it correct so you've got
two trajectories left you know for the
market to see and test and these days
you know this will only be saying when
you see earnings cut both for the
economy as well as of sectors so you
know the world is undergoing six months
to 12 months of paying because that's
when this whole story would unfold hi
vinay uh you know I wanted to ask you
about the two big themes you know the
pillars of the market the I.T space as
well as the banking space you know you
have been relatively cautious on the ID
space you have some exposure to emphasis
but I think the overall stance was
you're cautious so are you sticking with
that and also you have been buying
private sector bags but what about the
psos they are the ones that are really
moving have you allocated any money to
the PSU banking space that valuation
buyers have some comfort
sure so let's look at all these three
questions actually not two which you
said but first one the IIT space we are
underway the ID space because of the
same comment I made earlier uh the
interest rates in us have moved up the
two-year chart today at about 4.6
percent uh for USS compared to the
10-year chart which is at four percent
so there's a negative uh interest rate
between the two year and 10-year chart
which means there's a lot of pain in Us
in the short term when this occurs what
we typically believe is in the next six
to 12 months you'll see a Slowdown in
the orders given by the global
corporates to the I.T companies and you
could start seeing earnings getting
downgraded so we're sticking to that
stance of of being you know 50
underweight in the IIT space uh we like
the dollar play which is why the make in
India becomes a lot more important uh
you know wherever you have those
companies when you're getting exposure
to the dollar but having raw material
coming from the country our second theme
you know Banks uh if you look at the
loan book the banks every month it has
been inching up today it's close to 18
percent uh similar to last one 17.9 to
be precise now that number is fantastic
uh if if you compounded you're saying in
four years you're going to have the
rulebook growth doubled right from
today's level having said that the
interest rates also for India are moving
up but not as fast as the rest of the
world the capital adpc ratio for the big
banks in India the private banks are
between 18 to 22 23 which means they are
comfortable and they can capture growth
which is why we like the private Banks
having said that we also own uh the
biggest PSJA Bank in our portfolio and
we like it the results were fantastic of
SBI but uh incrementally uh what we're
seeing is in the private Banks we're
seeing a comfort level in valuations in
line with the uh public sector Banks but
more importantly the capital requisite
ratio is more comfortable which means
they can grow before they come to the
market to tap for more for equity
whenever the outside we must thank you
for joining us in the day when uh you
know the match is going on so thank you
very much you know for joining us uh
today on the uh show but you were
talking about the banking space
um just turning your attention to the
fmcg path in that you've picked our
consumer could you tell us why
uh lots of reasons apart from the fact
that I like coffee uh but you know
what's what's really important is if you
look at the way Tata consumer and the
new CEO who's not new anymore it's been
a year a couple of years there how he's
made the food chain grow out there you
know if you go to amazon.in and just put
data the number of products you will get
which is really made fmcg uh Ready Foods
uh is amazing the way the margins and
the salt business is growing uh is great
uh the way uh Starbucks is you know
going to get a lot more profitable in
the times to come the number of outlets
startups are still a trifle of what they
are in China and that's increasing so
you've got too many Triggers on uh for
Tata consumer which is leading to their
growth rate in earnings to being between
15 to 20 25 much higher than most of the
other fmcg names which is why we like
data consumer
what's your what's your view there I
mean actually it's one of the few
businesses where we are actually seeing
uh earnings estimates moving higher
that's right yeah what are the very few
sectors right otherwise even for sectors
like banking earnings are holding I mean
Autos earnings are holding they're not
Rising expectations but here they are
rising your thoughts
so I think perfect comment made by you
right our biggest concern for India to
one was the currency which I mentioned
earlier and second is the earnings
trajectory as inflation comes down we'll
start seeing earnings being cut by four
to five percent so you know we won't be
surprised if uh the Nifty EPS goes to
even 810 levels one year forward having
said that as far as bharti is concerned
bharti has the you know a three-prong
strategy the first strategy is just as
you keep on digitizing as you use more
and more of the data play the traffic
increases so that's the first thing make
a consumer uh who use a lot more of
gigabyte per day per month second is uh
you start moving to higher rpu customers
uh so the same person who is using
lesser in terms of data being given
unlimited at a point of time would get
charged so you know the rpu our two
times uh uh you know the customer you
get the revenue by increasing and the
third is increase the speed you know
move from 2G to 4G they have a lot of 2G
customers and from 4G to 5G so you give
better speed uh increase your usage and
charge a bit more you know the
ingredients of all this is higher
revenues incrementally if you see the
last couple of quarters the incremental
margin which comes on nutriental
revenues for bharti is way above their
40 you know it's closer to 60 to 70
because the variable costs you know are
limited and fixed and fixed costs you
know don't have more cost coming in uh
incrementally which means that you know
their margins will improve and that
that's why as you have your if it are
increasing your bottom line increases a
lot more further so we are very positive
bharti as well all right very quickly uh
when I you know you have also
highlighted that credit card spends are
picking up uh you know
a quick question is with regard to do
you play this theme other why are the
only listed credit card company or by
the banking space
you can do both uh so you know you can
play this game by the credit card
company listed place as well as the
banking space lots of the private Banks
uh kotak in particular you know have do
not have their listing and they own 100
of it uh ditto as well as icha so
technically you can play this uh you
play this theme of credit cards by using
the private bags which we like uh HDFC
is is a leader in in its in the credit
card space in India uh it had some
hiccups but it's back and we like that
company as well
of it and thank you very much for your
time it's a pleasure as always and a
great chat thank you very much
well that's uh Jason with his thoughts